Guide to the William Richard Johnson Papers
Yale University Divinity School Library
- Writings and Printed Material, 1906-1961, n.d.; Series II; 3' 6" (9 boxes)
  - "Rendition of the Kuling Estate," "Review of 'The Educational Frontier'," "Resolution of International Cooperation for Peace", 1936 (Box 27, Folder 15)
  - "General Chiang, Christian," "American Interest in the Far Eastern Crisis," Nanchang News Notes," "The Nanchang Academy " "The Development of Humanity...", 1937 (Box 27, Folder 16)
  - Incl.: "Relief Situation in Nanking," "War Relief Work...," "Observations on the Far Eastern Crisis...," "Protestantism in the Far East", 1938 (Box 27, Folder 17)
  - "Peace Propaganda in the United States", 1939 (Box 27, Folder 18)
  - "Some Observations on Peace ," "Nanchang News Notes", 1939 (Box 27, Folder 19)
  - "Christians Displace Communists: Re building China County", 1940 (Box 28, Folder 20)
  - "American Red Cross Relief Unit Report", 1941 (Box 28, Folder 21)
  - "On Board the Gripsholm," "Report of Made at Macho," "American Red Cross Relief," "Report...Kiangsi Province", 1942 (Box 28, Folder 22)
  - "The Siege of Hong Kong", 1943 (Box 28, Folder 23)
  - "Community War Fund," The New China in the New Pacific," "A Radio Prayer", 1944 (Box 28, Folder 24)
  - "Will Russia Supersede Japan As Aggressor in the Orient?", 1945 (Box 28, Folder 25)
  - "Ambassador Hurley ," "American Responsibility ..," "The Present Struggle...", 1945 (Box 28, Folder 26)
  - Incl.: "American Support of Soviet Aggression in China," "Problems of the Peace", 1946 (Box 28, Folder 27)
  - "We Lost the War at Yalta", 1946 (Box 28, Folder 28)
  - "Of What Significance is Thunder Out of China?" "Journeys Half-way Around the World," "The United States Sells China Down the Amur", 1947 (Box 28, Folder 29)
  - "The Moscow Line on China", 1947 (Box 28, Folder 30)
  - Incl.: "Should the United States China...?" "What Shall the General Conference Say About China", 1948
  - Incl.: "Falsehoods and Some Truths About China," "Open Letter to Bishop Moore and Missions Board", 1949 (Box 28, Folder 32)
  - Incl.: "China, Key to the Orient and to Asia" "An Open Letter to President Truman", 1950 (Box 29, Folder 33)
  - Incl.: "The Korean Crisis," "The Chinese Situation ", 1951 (Box 29, Folder 34)
  - Incl.: "Statement Before the United Senate...," "Recovery of China from the Reds," "Red China's Persecutions ", 1952 (Box 29, Folder 35)
  - "A New American China Policy," "China is a Hell on Earth", 1952 (Box 29, Folder 36)
  - "World War III," "Communist Persecution of Chinese Christians", 1952 (Box 29, Folder 37)
  - "The Methodist Church and China," " Peace or War" 1952 (Box 29, Folder 38)
  - "The Communication of Chinese Protestants", 1952 (Box 29, Folder 39)
  - Incl.: "The Crucifiction [sic], of the Chinese Church", 1953 (Box 29, Folder 40)
  - Incl.: "To the Un-American Activities Committee," "The United States' Betrayal of China to the Kremlin", 1954 (Box 29, Folder 41)
  - Incl.: "Should Red China be Recognized?", 1955 (Box 29, Folder 42)
  - Incl.: "Brief Summary of a Notice of a Release," "Persecution of Peiping's Pastor Wang Ming-Tao", 1956 (Box 29, Folder 43)
  - Incl.: "To the Delegates of the Methodist Conference," "To the Methodist Bishops," re: Johnson Receives Award, 1957, 1959-61 (Box 29, Folder 44)
  - Incl.:"A Real Man Hunt," "America's Conquest by Subversion Nears Completion," "Can Chinese Christianity Live in a Marxist Mould?", n.d. (Box 30, Folder 45)
  - "China at the Cross-Roads," "The China Crisis," "China Famine", n.d. (Box 30, Folder 46)
  - "China Missionary Confirms Atrocity Stories," "Comments on Professor J.W.D. Smith's Confidential Statement," "Development of Cooperatives", n.d. (Box 30, Folder 47)
  - Incl.: "Did the Chinese People Willingly Desert Their Constitutional Government" "English Objectives," "Episodes in China's Revolution", n.d. (Box 30, Folder 48)
  - "Generalissimo and Madame Chiang Kai shek," "Government Loans to Farmers," "In Search of Freedom" (Box 30, Folder 49)
  - "Khitans," "Questions from WRJ--Ans. by Job [C.K.] Shaw," "Measures Taken by Communist China", n.d. (Box 30, Folder 50)
  - "Memo for Hon. J. Parnell Thomas," "Memo Regarding Proposed Action," "Nanchang Academy", n.d.
  - "Our War in the East and the Post-War World," "Outline of a Proposed Plan for a Civilian Refugee Camp" (Box 30, Folder 52)
  - Incl.: "The Path to be Energetically Pursued," "Report of Kan River District," "Rural Reconstruction in Central China", n.d. (Box 30, Folder 53)
  - "Rural Reconstruction in China," "Secretary Acheson and the State Department's Soviet Union Policy," "Some Opposition Factors" (Box 30, Folder 54)
  - Incl.: Summary of Facts in Tsen's War Relief Work," "Was the State Department's China Policy Decisive", n.d. (Box 30, Folder 55)
  - Untitled; incl. a radio broadcast, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 56)
  - Incomplete, fragments, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 57-61)
  - Misc.: incl. lists, outlines, bibliography, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 62)
  - Incl.: "What I Saw of the Battleship Fleet in Cal." by Laura S. Buswell, 1909 (Box 31, Folder 64)
  - Incl.: "Training Children in Responsibility ," by Ina B. Johnson, "Anticipated", n.d. (Box 31, Folder 65)
  - "Fall of 1926" by Laura Johnson E. [Woodliff], n.d. (Box 31, Folder 66)
  - The Minutes of University of Nanking, "Letter from China," by Daisy M. Vaughan, "Action of Bd. of Trustees, William Nast College", 1909-1910 (Box 32, Folder 67)
  - "Constitution and By-Laws of the Educational Union," "Notes on Interview with Sun Yat-sen," "Minutes, Kiangsi Mission Meeting", 1911-1913 (Box 32, Folder 68)
  - "A Sick Man's Prayer Answered," "One College Among 26,000,000 People," "A Japanese Pro-German..." by T.I. Kamura, 1913-1915 (Box 32, Folder 69)
  - "Centenary Address," "A Program for the Stewardship Area Secretary", 1918 (Box 32, Folder 70)
  - "Japan and the War," by C.J.L. Bates, "Japan's Place in the Orient," by C.J.L. Bates, "The Twenty-One Demands on China," by G.J.L. Bates, 1918 (Box 32, Folder 71)
  - "Central Institutional Church, Nan chang," by F.C. Gale, "Nanchang Academy Catalogue and Announcements," with enclosures, 1919, 1923 (Box 32, Folder 72)
  - "Troy Conference Laymen in Action," "Critical Moments in the History of China," by H.F. MacNair, 1924-1925 (Box 32, Folder 73)
  - "Mrs. Brown's Diary of Nanchang Events", 1926-1927 (Box 32, Folder 74)
  - Incl.: Individual Accounts re: Nan king, "A Statement to Chinese Friends", 1927 (Box 32, Folder 75)
  - "The Protestant Breakdown in China," by Clifford J. King, translation of a pamphlet and speech by Chiang Kai shek, 1927 (Box 32, Folder 76)
  - Material re: China Famine Relief, Pray for China, 1928 (Box 32, Folder 77)
  - Re.: China Famine Relief, 1928 (Box 32, Folder 78-81)
  - Pray for China, re: China Famine Relief Committee, 1929 (Box 32, Folder 82)
  - "While Millions Starve," "Has the Red Cross Lost Its Soul?" "Concerning the Report of the American Red Cross", 1929 (Box 32, Folder 83)
  - "Piteous Appeals from China," China Inter national Famine Relief Commission Information Sheets, 1930 (Box 33, Folder 84)
  - Incl. re: Kiangsi International Famine Relief Committee, 1931 (Box 33, Folder 85)
  - Incl. re: Kiangsi International Famine Relief Committee, 1932 (Box 33, Folder 86)
  - Incl. re: Kiangsi International Famine Relief Committee, Memorandum re: Kuling, 1933 (Box 33, Folder 87)
  - Incl.: "Rural Service in Kiangsi," "Baldwin School, Nanchang," by Margaret Seeck, "Woman's Foreign Missionary Society," by Liu Tai Ching, 1934 (Box 33, Folder 88)
  - Incl.: "Rural Reconstruction in Kiangsi," Kuling Estate Council Minutes, Program of the Nanking Theological Seminary, 1935 (Box 33, Folder 89)
  - "Rules of the New Life Movement," transl. by Louis D. Tsai, "A Sociological View on Rural Reconstruction," by L.S. Hsu, "Kuling Estate Directory and General Information for Visitors", 1935 (Box 33, Folder 90)
  - Incl.: "Kiangsi Conference," "Rendition of the Estate," "Famine Commission Bulletin", 1936 (Box 33, Folder 91)
  - Incl.: "At Yenching University" by Grace M., "Notes...Between Univ. of Nanking and the Japanese Embassy," from M.S. Bates, 1937 (Box 33, Folder 92)
  - "Notes on the Immediate Situation", by M.S. Bates, "Short Articles on the Japanese Conquest," "Christian Work in the Changte, Honan Area," by G. Eadie, 1938 (Box 33, Folder 93)
  - Incl.: "As It Looked in North China February, 1938," An Address by Madame Chiang Kai-shek," "Madame Chiang...to Missionary Educationalists" 1938 (Box 33, Folder 94)
  - Incl. re: The Yungfeng Refugee Camp, 1939 (Box 33, Folder 95)
  - Incl. re: American Red Cross China Relief Unit, 1940 (Box 33, Folder 96)
  - Re: East Asia Conference, "Nanchang Academy and the War Emergency", 1942 (Box 33, Folder 97)
  - Incl.: "Journal of the Kiangsi Annual Conference of the Methodist Church," Re. Kiangsi Christian Rural Service Union, Before Final Victory, speeches by Generalissimo Chiang Kai-shek, 1943 (Box 33, Folder 98)
  - Incl. re: Kiangsi Christian Rural Service Union, "The Hong Kong Fellowship News Letter", 1944 (Box 33, Folder 99)
  - "W.A. Main," by B.H. Paddock, 1945 (Box 33, Folder 100)
  - Incl.: "Statement re: Mme. Sun Yatsen's Appeal," "Report on Johnson Memorial Church," by Chiu Yun-hai, Thunder Out of China, reviewed by Richard Watts, Jr., 1946 (Box 33, Folder 101)
  - Incl.: "Nanchang Notes" by Kimber H.K. Den, "Program and Resolutions...Methodist Federation for Social Action", 1947 (Box 33, Folder 102)
  - Incl.: "American Policy Toward China," by David Nelson Rowe, 1948 (Box 33, Folder 103)
  - Incl.: KCRSU Material, "Communism Challenges Christianity in China," by Bishop Carleton Lacy, 1949 (Box 33, Folder 104)
  - Incl.: "China U.S. Ammunition," "America's Surrender at Yalta," by Major Gen. Patrick J. Hurley, 1949 (Box 33, Folder 105)
  - Incl.: "A Pastoral Letter to Fellow-Christians from General Synod of Chung Hua Sheng Kung Hui," "Decisions on the Policies Promulgated by Chou En Lai, Chairman", 1950 (Box 33, Folder 106)
  - Incl.: "Report of Hsiangiang Project, KCRSU," "Should we Recognize Communist China?" by Geraldine Fitch, 1950 (Box 33, Folder 107)
  - Incl. "Manifesto for the Disposal of Missionary Institutions," "Declaration of the Peking Christian Conference", 1951 (Box 33, Folder 108)
  - Incl.: "Measures for the Disposal of American-Subsidized Christian Bodies," by Chou En Lai, "Communist Concentration Camp in Shanghai, by Peter Yen, 1951 (Box 33, Folder 109)
  - Incl.: "Plans for the Work of the Church in the Last Half of 1952," (Transl. text of the Summons of the Three Self Movement) (Box 34, Folder 110)
  - Incl.: "Crisis Leaflets," by MFSA, "A Letter to Presbyterians...adopted by the General Assembly", 1953 (Box 34, Folder 111)
  - Incl.: "Information from the Committee on Un-American Activities," "Statement Before the Ad Hoc Political Committee," by Dr. T.F. Tsiang, 1954 (Box 34, Folder 112)
  - Incl.: "Statement" by Dr. T.F. Tsiang, "Sermon" by Quentin K.Y. Huang, 1955 (Box 34, Folder 113)
  - Incl.: "Fractured Reasoning," an address by Madame Chiang Kai-shek, "Our Daughter Grace," by Edith Goruch and H.G. Smith, 1958, 1961 (Box 34, Folder 114)
  - Incl.: "Aid to China ," "Ambassador from China Describes China Famine Conditions," by Sao-Ke A. Sze, "American China Associates" (Box 35, Folder 115)
  - Incl.: "A Deed of Lease Issued by Ching", n.d. (Box 35, Folder 116)
  - Incl.:"Dr. Kahn's Last Days'" "Japanese Attitude Toward the 'Chinese Affair'," by C.A. Hogg, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 117)
  - Incl.: "Memorandum as to Status for Kuling Estate," "Plea for Peace and Conciliation," by Fuko-An (Box 35, Folder 118)
  - Incl.:"Porcelain Tract'," by Leland W. Holland (Box 35, Folder 119)
  - Incl.: "A Study of the MFSA," by Ben, "The Social Problem," by Elwood, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 120)
  - Incomplete, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 121)
  - Untitled, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 122)
  - Church Bulletins, 1922-1966, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 123)
  - Chinese Language Material, 1927, 1936, 1937 (Box 35, Folder 124)
  - Chinese Language Material, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 125-127)
  - Miscellaneous: incl. lists and songs (Box 35, Folder 128)
- Notes and Notebooks, 1887-1966, n.d.; Series III; 3' 6" (9 boxes)
  The material in this series is arranged alphabetically: address books and lists, card file, date books, diaries, and notes. Within each group, the contents are arranged chronologically with undated material found at the end. Mrs. Johnson's material, found following Mr. Johnson's, consists of address books, diaries, and notes.
  - Address books, 1943, 1945,1949, 1952, 1962, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Address lists (arranged alphabetically by state), n.d. (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - Address lists, incl. family, Chinese friends, senators and congressmen (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - Address lists, incl. Nanchang Academy donors, ministers and missionaries (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - Card file, 1950-1953, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - Date Books, 1919, 1928,1935-1938,1931, 1933,1943, 1944,1947, 1955 1963, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - Diaries, 1887, 1890-1894, 1888,1896, 1898 (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - Diary, 1905-1907 (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - Diary, 1908, 1938 (Box 38, Folder 9)
  - Notes, 1908-1920 (Box 39, Folder 10-16)
  - Notes, 1921-1922 (Box 40, Folder 17)
  - Notes re: East Asia Conference, 1923 (Box 40, Folder 18)
  - Notes Incl., 1923 (Box 40, Folder 19)
  - Notes incl. re: General Conference, 1924 (Box 40, Folder 20)
  - Notes incl. "Peiping Trip," "Board of Education", 1925-1926 (Box 40, Folder 21)
  - Notes, 1927-1928 (Box 40, Folder 22-23)
  - Notes incl. class notes, 1929 (Box 40, Folder 24)
  - Notes, 1930-1932 (Box 40, Folder 25-27)
  - Notes incl. re: Rural Reconstruction Plan, 1933 (Box 41, Folder 28)
  - Notes, 1934-1938 (Box 41, Folder 29-32)
  - Notes, 1941-1949 (Box 42, Folder 33-36)
  - Notes, 1950-1966, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 37-43)
  - Notes, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 44-47)
  - Address books-IBJ, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 48)
  - Diaries-IBJ, 1922, 1925 (Box 44, Folder 49)
  - Notes-IBJ, 1961, n d. (Box 44, Folder 50)
  - Notes-IBJ, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 51)
- Financial and Legal Material, 1901-1966; Series IV; 1' 8" (4 boxes)
  The first three boxes in this series contain the personal financial and legal material of William and Ina Johnson, and the contents are arranged chronologically. Non-personal material is contained in the last box of the series.
  - Personal: Deed to the Buswell farm, Polo, Illinois, 1901 (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - Personal: Power of attorney statement-WRJ, 1908 (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - Personal: Abstract of title, Buswell farm, 1912 (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - Personal: Cash books 1914-1916, 1917-1919, 1912-1915 (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - Personal: incl. lease, Quit-Claim Deed, 1922,1924,1925, 1928 1931 (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - Personal: incl. cash book, 1931-1937 (Box 45, Folder 6)
  - Personal: incl. ledger book, 1934-1945 (Box 45, Folder 7)
  - Personal: incl. cash books 1944-1948, 1941-1949 (Box 45, Folder 8)
  - Personal, 1943 (Box 45, Folder 9)
  - Personal: incl. cash book, 1946-1949 (Box 45, Folder 10)
  - Personal: incl. bank book, 1950, 1951 (Box 45, Folder 11)
  - Personal: incl. ledger book, 1952, 1952-1960 (Box 45, Folder 12)
  - Personal: incl. cash book, 1953 (Box 46, Folder 13)
  - Personal, 1954-1956 (Box 46, Folder 14)
  - Personal: Quit-Claim Deed, 1956 (Box 46, Folder 15)
  - Personal, 1957-1961 (Box 46, Folder 16-20)
  - Personal, 1962 (Box 47, Folder 21)
  - Personal: incl. IBJ's will, 1963 (Box 47, Folder 22)
  - Personal, 1964 (Box 47, Folder 23)
  - Personal: incl. cash book, 1965 (Box 47, Folder 24)
  - Personal, 1966 (Box 47, Folder 25)
  - Personal, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 26)
  - Non-personal: incl. budgets, reports re Mission, 1911, 1914 1920,1926,1930, 1933 1939, 1941 (Box 48, Folder 27)
  - Non-personal: "Memorandum of Agreement between Nanchang Academy Building Committee", 1925 (Box 48, Folder 28)
  - Non-personal: "Agreement for the Rendition of the Kuling Estate to the Kiangsi Provincial Government", 1935 (Box 48, Folder 29)
  - Non-personal: incl. Mission finances .53, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 30)
- Personal Items and Memorabilia, 1878-1966, n.d..; Series V; 1' 8" (4 boxes)
  This section contains a variety of material, arranged alphabetically according to form (e.g., Biographical Information, Cards, Photographs).
  - Biog. information, notes, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 1)
  - Biog. info., newspaper clippings re: family, 1949, 1954, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 2)
  - Biog. info. re: Benjamin R. Johnson, 1897, 1908 (Box 49, Folder 3)
  - Biog. info., newspaper clippings, 1943 (Box 49, Folder 4)
  - Biog. info., newspaper clippings re: IBJ and WRJ, 1903,1942,1956 (Box 49, Folder 5)
  - Biog. info., newspaper clippings re: talks by WRJ, 1940, 1944 (Box 49, Folder 6)
  - Biog. info. re.family of IBJ, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 7)
  - Biog. info. about WRJ, by Bishop Bashford and P.S. Selwyn-Clarke, 1913,1942 (Box 49, Folder 8)
  - Announcements, 1939-1965 (Box 49, Folder 9)
  - Autograph albums, 1885,1890 (Box 49, Folder 10)
  - Birth certificate-WRJ, 1878 (Box 49, Folder 11)
  - Bon-voyage book for Laura S. Buswell, on her trip to China, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 12)
  - Cards, calling and greeting (family), 1896, 1962 1964, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 13)
  - Cards (IBJ) incl. Mother-Daughter Banquet, 1953,1963 (Box 49, Folder 14)
  - Cards, incl. Social Security, Identification and Service cards, 1918-1964, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 15)
  - Certificate of baptism, 1962,1964 (Box 49, Folder 16)
  - Chinese post cards, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 17)
  - Chinese Greeting cards, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 18)
  - Citation, Newspaper Clippings and Award to WRJ by the Ministry of Interior, Republic of China, 1962 (Box 50, Folder 19)
  - Cook book-IBJ, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 20)
  - Currency incl. Chinese, 1915, 1918, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 21)
  - Deacon's credentials-WRJ 1908 (Box 50, Folder 22)
  - Deportment post cards, 1886, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 23)
  - Elder's credentials-WRJ, 1908 (Box 50, Folder 24)
  - Fork used by father of IBJ in the Civil War, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 25)
  - Forms, 1942, 1950, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 26)
  - Genealogical Information, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 27)
  - Guest lists and menus from various ships, 1925, 1940 (Box 50, Folder 28)
  - Handkerchief-IBJ (Box 50, Folder 29)
  - Invitations, 1897-1955, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 30)
  - Last words of Benjamin R. Johnson, 1908 (Box 51, Folder 31)
  - Re. lectures and itinerary, 1943-1946, n.d. (Box 51, Folder 32)
  - List of family names at Lake Corey, 1965 (Box 51, Folder 33)
  - Local Preacher's license, 1905 (Box 51, Folder 34)
  - Maps and drawings, 1926-1932, n.d. (Box 51, Folder 35-37)
  - Marriage certificate, wedding book and invitation, 1906 (Box 51, Folder 38)
  - Medical reports of the family, 1929,1936,1940,1947,1954,1960 (Box 51, Folder 39)
  - Miscellaneous, 1934,1941,1963, n.d. (Box 51, Folder 40)
  - National Conference ribbon, 1918 (Box 51, Folder 41)
  - Northwestern University Alumni Association-Award of Merit, 1940 (Box 51, Folder 42)
  - Pen used by B.M. Consul General C.G. Moss in signing Sino-British agreement on Dec. 31, 1935 (Box 52, Folder 43)
  - Photographs: buildings, mostly in China, 1897,1904,1938, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 44)
  - Photographs: Chinese individuals, 1922,1923,1964, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 45)
  - Photographs: incl. Japanese atrocities in China, 1937 (Box 52, Folder 46)
  - Photographs: incl. family, 1953,1963,1964, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 47)
  - Polo Telephone Directory, 1950, 1955 (Box 52, Folder 48)
  - Programs and menus- IBJ, 1927,1941,1946 (Box 52, Folder 49)
  - Incl. programs for services and celebrations, 1900-1958, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 50)
  - Report cards, 1885,1894,1928, 1929 (Box 52, Folder 51)
  - Shanghai Tiffin Club-list of members, 1928 (Box 52, Folder 52)
  - Tin-type of B.R. Johnson, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 53)
  - War-time souvenirs incl. Prisoner of War ticket, War Ration Book, 1942, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 54)